Lowell Thomas Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Lowell Thomas Papers: Sound Recordings
1789 - 1984
1900 - 1981
npkmc-227-251
1203 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Thomas, Lowell, 1892-1981
The Lowell Thomas Papers encompasses a wide range of materials documenting the life, family, and professional career of Lowell Thomas. These materials include correspondence, administrative and financial documents, manuscripts, printed materials, photographic materials, motion picture films, audio recordings, and memorabilia.
Collection Overview
Divided into nine subseries, this series consists of reel-to-reel audio tapes, phonograph records, audio cassettes, and other types of sound recordings. The subseries are arranged by form of material. Subseries 1 - 4 are divided further into sub subseries arranged by subject, and each includes recordings that pertain to Thomas's major professional projects. Information regarding the content of each recording is taken from [the recording's container]. A project to digitize these recordings is on-going. Researchers should consult with the archivist regarding the available digital versions.
The Lowell Thomas Papers were donated to Marist College by the Thomas family in 2006.
Historical Note
Lowell Jackson Thomas was born in Woodington, Ohio on 6 April 1892 to two school teachers, Harry G. Thomas and Harriet Wagner Thomas. The family did not remain in Darke County, Ohio for very long because Lowell's father wanted to become a doctor. Harry G. Thomas's pursuit of a medical degree led the family to Kirkman, Iowa where five-year-old Lowell was enrolled in school for the first time. Harry's studies soon led him to the University of Nebraska. Upon graduation, Harry G. Thomas followed his brother's suggestion to begin his medical practice in the twin mining boom towns of Cripple Creek and Victor, Colorado. It was here in the rugged American West that Lowell spent the better part of his childhood and young adult years.
Read more
There are no restrictions on this collection
Related Collections
Lowell Thomas Film Collection
Lowell Thomas Memorabilia Collection
Lowell Thomas Papers: Graphic Materials
Lowell Thomas Papers: Objects
Lowell Thomas Papers: Textual Materials
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into nine series: 1) Reel-to-Reel audio tape, has 16 subseries, 2. Phonograph Records, has eight subseries, 3. Audio Cassettes, has nine subseries, 4) 16 millimeter magnetic tape, has two subseries, 5) SoundScriber recordings, 6) Flexographs, 7) Dictabelt Recordings, 8) Wire Recordings, and 9) 8-Track cartridge
The Marist College Archives and Special Collections staff wishes to express their deep appreciation to all of the parties that helped the Lowell Thomas Project come to fruition.
Read more
- 1. Reel-to-Reel audio tape, 1934 - 1981; 1; Boxes: 1744 - 1818
  Series contains Lowell Thomas and the News, The Best Years, Tibet, High Adventure with Lowell Thomas, Flight to Adventure, Lowell Thomas radio inserts, music and song, personalities, Lowell Thomas, Jr., Speeches, Flight to South Pole, banquets, interviews, Alaska, personal, and miscellany.
  Subject
  - Subseries 1.1: Lowell Thomas and the News, 1937 - 1976; 1.1; Boxes: 1744 - 1749
    Chronological
    - Lowell Thomas Radio News Broadcast, 1937 April 30 (Folder 1744.01, Box 1744)
      1. April 30, 1937 2. For Sunoco 3. Opening 4. Commercial 5. Captain Valentine Williams and news 6. Lowell Thomas from S.S. Europa - mid-Atlantic 7. Opening 8. Commercial 9. News and Lowell Thomas from Paris, France 10. Close
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, circa 1937 (Folder 1744.02, Box 1744)
      1. May 12, 1937; 2. For Sunoco; 3. From London on Coronation; 4. May 14, 1937; 5. Lowell Thomas for Sunoco from Paris and Premier Blum
    - Lowell Thomas Radio News Broadcast, 1937 May 18 (Folder 1744.03, Box 1744)
      1. May 18, 1937 2. For Sunoco 3. Lowell Thomas from Southampton, England - regular news cast 4. Lowell Thomas from mid-Atlantic on board Queen Mary - George Sokolsky from New York
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, circa 1937 (Folder 1744.04, Box 1744)
      1. For Sunoco 2. Regular news program - Edward Tomlinson substituting for Lowell Thomas, who is traveling in West (static) 3. Lowell Thomas - from Denver - regular program; strikes, war scare, the Windsors, Governor Adams, British Derby, “Dizzy” Dean suspended by Ford Frick
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1945 (Folder 1744.05, Box 1744)
      Lowell Thomas for Sun Oil Hugh James, announcer Short wave portion: Lowell Thomas overseas during World War II, Hamlin Burning - looks for Les Ward - Bombers hit Munich - Tale of Thunderbolt vs. Germanship - Hugh Gibson reports the news - report of S.W. above
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1948 June 28 (Folder 1744.06, Box 1744)
      For Ivory 1. Recorded from wire to tape 2. Tito 3. Airlift 4. King Proc. 5. London strike 6. Japan Quake 7. Inductions 8. Dewey/Warren 9. Pritchard broadcast 10. Nelson case 11. Announcement for Ivory
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1953 June (Folder 1744.07, Box 1744)
      Nelson Case for Procter & Gamble, opening and closing “Ivory” commercials Aired over CBS June 8th, 1953 Digital Copy Blank [reel too?]
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1955 April 27 (Folder 1744.08, Box 1744)
      Hugh Holder announcing For Delco Three minute - five second portion on Hannes Schneider Recorded at KSL, Salt Lake City, Utah
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1955 August 10 (Folder 1744.09, Box 1744)
      1) Commercial and introduction, Hugh Holder announcing 2) Lowell Thomas - Hurricane Connie 3) Lowell Thomas Naval Campaign - Pacific 4) Lowell Thomas - Vietnam Lowell Thomas - Korea upheaval 5) Lowell Thomas - Goa - Hindu invasion 6) Radiation runaway - Heller 7) Mass. - Polio 8) Hoover - 81 years 9) FBI - solves robbery 10) New Jersey Prison - returnee 11) Beauty and Talent As aired over CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1956 (Folder 1744.10, Box 1744)
      For Delco, Joe Gibbon announcer Walter Cronkite Substituting Insert: Lowell Thomas from cable car en route Caracas from Mount Avila Hotel October 3rd, 1956 Aired on CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 June 18 (Folder 1744.11, Box 1744)
      1. CBS Radio 2. 6:45 - 7:00 p.m. 3. Wednesday, June 18
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 July 2 (Folder 1744.12, Box 1744)
      Ned Calmer substituting “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas” insert (Hawaii) Complete broadcast for July 2, 1957
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 July 25 (Folder 1744.13, Box 1744)
      Ned Calmer substituting 1. Explosion on plane over Mojave Desert - unknown source 2. No Federal School Aid, Bill failed because of anti-segregation clause 3. Atomic test shot over Nevada desert code - Owens 4. Ruler of Tunisia removed, proclaimed Republic 5. Civil Rights Bill debated in Senate 6. Batista Government in Cuba cracking down on rebel bond selling 7. President Eisenhower requests Americans traveling abroad be Goodwill Ambassadors 8. Red Grange testifies on Professional Draft, he disagrees 9. Rocket will be launched into space in September 10. Wheeler found guilty of disobedience, but Coronel threw out case 11. US Sailor in jail went AWOL, took Airplane, almost crashed over Pacific 12. Federal Plan for control of Rockets and Guided missiles - Arms Talks 13. British Jets bomb rebellious Muscat and Oman 14. Arizona farmers ignored federal regulations and built bridge and charged tolls 15. Anti-Soviet riots in Poznan [Posen], Poland 16. Professional Wrestler Richard O’Reilly turn to crime for money Aired over CBS - 7/25/57
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 July 26 (Folder 1744.14, Box 1744)
      Ned Calmer substituting (no insert) Aired on CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 1 (Folder 1744.15, Box 1744)
      Walter Cronkite substituting 1. Lowell Thomas: (6:45 - 7:00) 2. Walter Cronkite 3. For Air Thursday Aug 1st, 1957
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 5 (Folder 1744.16, Box 1744)
      “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas,” Radio Inserts from Australia 1957 Inserted as part of complete broadcast with Walter Cronkite. Aired on CBS 8-5-57
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 5 (Folder 1744.17, Box 1744)
      1. Monday August 5, 1957 2. Opens “Have you heard how unpopular Americans are around the world these days…” 3. Spliced original - duplicate should be made for air
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 6 (Folder 1745.01, Box 1745)
      “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas”, Radio Inserts from New Guinea 1. New Guinea 1957 2. Port Moresby - Fay[?] River Papuan natives. Tells of trip to Port Moresby 3. Inserted as portion of complete broadcast 4. Aired on CBS 8-6-57
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 6 (Folder 1745.02, Box 1745)
      1. Tuesday August 6, 1957 2. Opens “Hello everybody…” 3. Closes “So long until tomorrow”
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 7 (Folder 1745.03, Box 1745)
      Walter Cronkite substituting “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas” inserts from North side of New Guinea (Mostly Generalities - 2 cuts) Aired on CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 8 (Folder 1745.04, Box 1745)
      Walter Cronkite substituting “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas” insert from New Guinea (Markham Valley parachute landings) John Gilmore Aired on CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 15 (Folder 1745.05, Box 1745)
      Walter Cronkite substituting “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas” insert from New Guinea (Sepik River), broadcast on CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 16 (Folder 1745.06, Box 1745)
      Walter Cronkite substituting “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas” insert from New Guinea (Sepik River) - “OOKS Snook, Skipper of Flagship” - (Story of Native meeting Halls) Aired on CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 19 (Folder 1745.07, Box 1745)
      Walter Cronkite substituting “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas” insert from New Guinea - Sepik River Village of “Timboki” - Story of first motion picture shown there Aired on CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 20 (Folder 1745.08, Box 1745)
      Walter Cronkite substituting “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas” insert from New Guinea (Nano, Chief of MOA) (May River) Aired on CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 21 (Folder 1745.09, Box 1745)
      Walter Cronkite substituting “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas” insert (Sepik river home of Peter O’Sullivan) New Guinea, Central Depression Aired on CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 22 (Folder 1745.10, Box 1745)
      Walter Cronkite substituting “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas” insert from New Guinea Jungle, home of Peter O’Sullivan Aired on CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 August 23 (Folder 1745.11, Box 1745)
      Walter Cronkite substituting “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas” inserts from New Guinea (food drop from plane) Aired on CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 3 (Folder 1745.12, Box 1745)
      1. CBS Radio 2. 6:45 - 7:00 p.m. 3. Safety copy for Mary Davis
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 4 (Folder 1745.13, Box 1745)
      1. 6:45 - 7:00 p.m. 2. Tech. - M. Goldberg
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 4 (Folder 1745.14, Box 1745)
      1. 6:45 - 7:00 p.m.
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 5 (Folder 1745.15, Box 1745)
      From A.C.S. Building in Elmendorf Air Force Base CBS - 9/5/57
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 6 (Folder 1746.01, Box 1746)
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 9 (Folder 1746.02, Box 1746)
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 10 (Folder 1746.03, Box 1746)
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 11 (Folder 1746.04, Box 1746)
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 12 (Folder 1746.05, Box 1746)
      1. CBS Radio 2. 6:45 - 7:00 p.m.
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 13 (Folder 1746.06, Box 1746)
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 16 (Folder 1746.07, Box 1746)
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 17 (Folder 1746.08, Box 1746)
      1. 6:45 - 7:00 p.m. 2. Tech. - M. Weiman
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September19 (Folder 1746.09, Box 1746)
      1. 6:45 - 7:00 p.m. 2. Tech. - Koppels
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September20 (Folder 1747.01, Box 1747)
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 30 (Folder 1747.02, Box 1747)
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 October 28 (Folder 1747.03, Box 1747)
      “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas” insert returns to air (Africa TV series) - (insert Lowell Thomas on equator en route Timbuktu) Aired over CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 October 30 (Folder 1747.04, Box 1747)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. substituting (with insert from Africa on Pygmies) “Ubangi Duck Bill People” - “Bungi on the Ubangi River” - (High Adventure Delco Series) Timbuktu Aired on CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 November 1 (Folder 1747.05, Box 1747)
      Lowell Thomas (regular program) with “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas” insert of “sound diary” - A report from Timbuktu camels - camels - camels and Lowell Thomas Aired on CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 November 7 (Folder 1747.06, Box 1747)
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 December 5 (Folder 1747.07, Box 1747)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. substituting Delco Program as aired (Joe Gibbon announcer) “High Adventure with Lowell Thomas,” Sr. insert: From Africa, completing report on Timbuktu - American missionaries David & Frank Marshall & wives Aired over CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1958 May 15 (Folder 1747.08, Box 1747)
      1) For Delco 2) Don Morocco 3) De Gaulle, Algeria 4) Lebanon 5) Moscow, Nasser 6) Nixon Welcome, Latin America Incident 7) Pearson, Canada 8) Philippine bases 9) Eisenhower 10) Sputnik III 11) Comm[ercial] 12) Sir Vivian Fuchs 13) Close May 15th, 1958 Aired over CBS
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 September 10 (Folder 1747.09, Box 1747)
      1. CBS Radio 2. 6:45 - 7:00 p.m. 3. Air Dub
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1957 October 28 (Folder 1747.10, Box 1747)
      1. Secretary of State John Foster Dulles news conference, Soviet internal struggles and threat of aggression 2. US ministers acceptance of gifts from foreign leaders 3. Khrushchev won control of Soviet Union 4. Bombing of Israeli Parliament - escaped from mental hospital, Prime Minister Ben-Gurion only slightly injured 5. Prime Minister MacMillan wishes to meet Eisenhower at NATO conference 6. Dr. Earnest Lawrence won Fermi Award, invented cyclotron 7. Atomic Submarine went to North Pole, under ice 8. Lowell Thomas insert from Africa 9. Louis B. Mayer dies Recorded 10/29/57
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, circa 1960 (Folder 1747.11, Box 1747)
      1. Indiana’s right to work bill outlawing Union shop 2. New Secretary of the Navy 3. Israeli withdrawal from Gaza and Secretary of State John Foster Dulles and Prime Minister Golda Meir 4. Vice President Nixon greeted in Rabat, Morocco 5. Investigation into fall of Nationalist China, Communists in Washington, failure of American Aid. Harry Dexter White former Asst. Secretary to the Treasury block aid transfer 6. From Truckee, Lake Tahoe - Winter Olympic Games - 1960 Squaw Valley 7. Dimitri Tiomkin - Cinerama
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1961 January 31 (Folder 1747.12, Box 1747)
      Laugh sequence at end of program
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, circa 1961 March (Folder 1747.13, Box 1747)
      Lowell Thomas regular program from Denver 1) Thompson Interview - 2) State Dept 3) Rio 4) Congo 5) Russian orbit 6) Jap mine 7) Weather - blizzard [not on tape] 8) Kennedy - Italy [not on tape] 9) Ken Leigh [not on tape] 10) Helen Hayes Salute to KLZ (runs over) [not on tape]
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1961 March 13 (Folder 1747.14, Box 1747)
      (number 31 is 600 feet) March 13, 1961: Lowell Thomas regular program from Salt Lake City, Utah (simulates lodge origination) 27 seconds dead air - 2:01 fill from New York City March 14, 1961: Lowell Thomas from Alta Lodge [Peruvian] (?) runs over - on mike cough. March 13th - 14th, 1961
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1962 May 28 (Folder 1748.01, Box 1748)
      for Oldsmobile; from Anchorage regarding Ice Island 1. Commercial (Dick Noel) 2. Lowell Thomas from Alaska - U of K anniversary 3. Scott Carpenter, Colorado 4. Algeria gun battle 5. Raoul Salan; De Gaulle 6. Dutch mop up at Fak Fak 7. Isle of Jersey - poison gas 8. Seattle fair 9. Commercial 10. Lowell Thomas - Seattle Fair 11. Closing 12. Aired on CBS June 1, 1962
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1962 June 1 (Folder 1748.02, Box 1748)
      for Olds; from Alaska, University of Alaska anniversary 1. Commercial (Dick Noel) 2. From Alaska - Soviet cost of living 3. Algerian truce 4. Murder by berserk patient 5. Eisenhower/Humphrey 6. Anniversary of the Windsors which leads in to “Ice Island” and Lowell Thomas, Jr. 7. Satellite OSO 8. Commercial for Oldsmobile 9. Lowell Thomas on “Atomic Party in Hawaii” 10. Closing
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1962 August 30 (Folder 1748.03, Box 1748)
      1. Mystic Seaport, Connecticut 2. On board “Bowdoin” 3. Regarding Admiral Donald B. McMillan 4. Dick Noel for Oldsmobile
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, circa 1962 (Folder 1748.04, Box 1748)
      Revolution in Venezuela, Soviet diplomacy, 4th Nuclear explosion at Christmas Island, Cosmonaught boasting Soviet has largest steel mill at Magnitogorsk
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1963 January 3 (Folder 1748.05, Box 1748)
      For Oldsmobile 1. As aired over CBS January 3, 1963 2. Soviet; Convoy; U-2 revised; South Vietnam; De Gaulle; Pentagon; Income tax cut; Australia insert (Monsteriodelisioso; (commercial, Dick Noel, Oldsmobile) 3. Recorded for broadcast
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1963 June 6 (Folder 1748.06, Box 1748)
      May 15, 1963 Thomas, 5 outs: 2:17, 2:30, 2:19, 2:28, 2:28, 9.5 speed, 12 min Track 1 - May 24, 1963, Robert College (audio - 000-029) Track 2 - May 27, 1963, Impressions - Near East - (030-064) Track 3 - May 28, 1963, More Near East Impressions (066-097.5) Track 4 - May 29, 1963, Iraq - Saudi Arabia (100-134.5) Track 5 - May 30, 1963, Taj-Nashville (136-172)
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1963 June 9 (Folder 1748.07, Box 1748)
      1. Ceylon 2. Tech. - Nicks
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1963 June 11 (Folder 1748.08, Box 1748)
      Audio track, 1) speed: 000-052, More New Guinea 2) speed: 053-105.5, Leahy 3) speed: 108-170, Future of New Guinea 4) speed: 174-265, Sir E. Hallstrom 5) speed: 269-end, Bangkok
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1963 November 7 (Folder 1748.09, Box 1748)
      1. Hottlett on Lowell Thomas’s collaboration
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1963 November 25, December 12 (Folder 1748.10, Box 1748)
      1. Lowell Thomas on death of President Kennedy - 11/25/63 2. Lowell Thomas, first program from Hawaii - 12/18/63
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1963 December 19-20 (Folder 1748.11, Box 1748)
      1) Lowell Thomas - regular program from Hawaii (intact) features story on Stella Dysart. December 19, 1963 2) Lowell Thomas from Hawaii. Regular program. Story on “Doughboys.” December 20, 1963
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1963 December 23-27 (Folder 1748.12, Box 1748)
      Oldsmobile commercial (Dick Novel) Lowell Thomas program, December 1963
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, circa 1963 (Folder 1748.13, Box 1748)
      From Honolulu, celebrating the New Year with fireworks, Tour of Berlin Wall, in 1963 young women swam across to West Berlin, economic boom in Honolulu
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1964 April 6, 1967 June 23 (Folder 1748.14, Box 1748)
      1. April 6, 1964 (McArthur) 2. June 23, 1967
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1965 April (Folder 1748.15, Box 1748)
      1. Excerpt from “Lowell Thomas and the News” 2. Regular program noise and phone interference 3. Edward R. Murrow Obituary
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1965 July 5 (Folder 1748.16, Box 1748)
      Regular program for Olds; “Salute to 10th Mt. Division anniversary…July 5, 1965
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1965 December 31 (Folder 1749.01, Box 1749)
      For Buick 1. Salute to Townsend and Calmer 2. Mary Davis Obituary and news for December 31 1965
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1966 April 14 - May 3 (Folder 1749.02, Box 1749)
      Regular program without commentary from WBRK for CBS April 14, 1966 (Felix von Luckner obituary) 2) Regular program from Pawling Studios recorded and piped to CBS, New York for broadcast May 3, 1966
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1966 (Folder 1749.03, Box 1749)
      U.S. Steel increasing prices, investigation on soaring food prices, U.S. Cavalry Patrol in Vietnam, Operation Paul Revere, Increase in Draft, Ending of Indonesian-Malaysian War, Lennon states Beatles more popular than Jesus, Brain examination of Mass-murderer Charles Whitman, Harry Truman returns from hospital, Cave-Squatting record Cheddar Caverns, French Fashion - Salvador Dali look, 21st birthday of Steven Adam - criminal charges - “may wish he’d never been born” 8/4/66
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1968 December 26 (Folder 1749.04, Box 1749)
      From Lake Placid, New York LT reg. Lake Placid Club, Lt ret. awl on first day, Gene’ vacation ended, Vac. short by one week but did program anyhow First of Four, 12/26/68
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1968 (Folder 1749.05, Box 1749)
      President Lyndon Johnson, News conference on Vietnam Fighting outside of Saigon, search for Scorpion, lost Nuclear Submarine, Europe’s failed first lung transplant, Changes on French Cabinet, Presidential Primary in Oregon, race for around the world flight, Billy Mitchell, Obituary, Jack Harding
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1969 January 9 (Folder 1749.06, Box 1749)
      News reported by Lowell Thomas on Vice President Spiro Agnew’s visit to Singapore, killings in Milan, President‘s birthday in White House, Lake Placid Kennedy Memorial Winter Games, Hijacked airlines, Max Conrad, weather report and driving education
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1969 June 24 (Folder 1749.07, Box 1749)
      1. Originating at the Human Resources Center, Alberson, L.I. 2. Mr. Henry Viscardi, Jr., President 3. Copy posted June 26, 1969
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, 1969 October 10 (Folder 1749.08, Box 1749)
      1. Recorded in Hong Kong 2. Duplicate is on 1st part of tape, original affixed on 2nd part 3. Flying the Pacific 4. Undersea Makai 5. Chinn Ho 6. Micronesia Mulahey 7. Bullet Train 8. Olympic 9. Hong Kong 10. Hong Kong Marden 11. Macau
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, circa late 1950s - 1960 (Folder 1749.09, Box 1749)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. substituting President Eisenhower returning after illness, Adlai Stevenson may attend NATO conference in Paris, Striking Bus drivers in Southern California, from Amman little progress on settling Jordanian-Israeli dispute, British manufacturing, Intermediate Ballistic Missiles, Accident in Helsinki, Soviet plane runs off runway, discovered magnetic mine in Belgian harbor, Lowell Thomas, Jr. interviewed by Martha Deane, on Anchorage, Alaska,
    - Lowell Thomas Radio Inserts, 1970 December 21 (Folder 1749.10, Box 1749)
      Lowell Thomas to Alaska, 14 pieces
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News”, circa 1975 (Folder 1749.11, Box 1749)
      Lowell Thomas radio broadcast, anti-Cuban campaign, President Ford mobilizes soldiers, addressing rumors of retirement
    - “Lowell Thomas and the News” - Final Broadcast, 1976 May 14 (Folder 1749.12, Box 1749)